Take a journey to the heart of the universe.
Contact is a drama, science fiction, mystery film directed by Robert Zemeckis.
A radio astronomer receives the first extraterrestrial
radio signal ever picked up on Earth.
As the world powers scramble to decipher the message and decide upon a course of action, she
must make some difficult decisions between her beliefs, the truth, and reality.
Ellie Arroway, played by Jodie Foster.
Palmer Joss, played by Matthew McConaughey.
Michael Kitz, played by James Woods.
S. R. Hadden, played by John Hurt.
David Drumlin, played by Tom Skerritt.
Kent, played by William Fichtner.
Contact is a 1997 American science fiction drama film co-produced and
directed by Robert Zemeckis, based on the 1985 novel by Carl Sagan.
It stars Jodie Foster as Dr.
Eleanor "Ellie" Arroway, a SETI scientist who finds evidence of
extraterrestrial life and is chosen to make first contact.
Matthew McConaughey, James Woods, Tom Skerritt, William Fichtner, John Hurt,
Angela Bassett, Rob Lowe, Jake Busey, and David Morse co-star.
It features the Very Large Array in New Mexico, the Arecibo Observatory in Puerto Rico,
the Mir space station, and the Space Coast surrounding Cape Canaveral.
Sagan and his wife, Ann Druyan, began working on Contact in 1979.
They wrote a film treatment and set up the project at Warner Bros.
with Peter Guber and Lynda Obst as producers.
When development stalled, Sagan published Contact as a novel in
1985, and the film reentered development in 1989.
Roland Joffé and George Miller planned to direct, but
Joffé dropped out in 1993, and Warner Bros.
fired Miller in 1995.
With Zemeckis as director, filming ran from September 1996 to
February 1997, while Sony Pictures Imageworks, Weta, Ltd.
and Industrial Light & Magic (ILM) handled the visual and special effects.
Sagan died before the film was completed.
Contact was released on July 11, 1997, and received positive reviews, winning the
Hugo Award for Best Dramatic Presentation and two Saturn Awards.
It grossed over $171 million worldwide.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, nasa,
extraterrestrial technology, new mexico, prime number.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking and mind_bending.